<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <atom:link href="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <title>TurtleP.github.io</title>
    <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/</link>
    <description>Gamer &amp; Turtle</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 04:31:45 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 04:31:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>vuepress-plugin-feed2</generator>
    <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Fixes, Features, and a Little LÖVE</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2024-11-15-love-potion-upgrades.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2024-11-15-love-potion-upgrades.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Fixes, Features, and a Little LÖVE</source>
      <description>Fixes, Features, and a Little LÖVE Hello everyone, hope you&amp;apos;re doing well! It&amp;apos;s been a minute since I posted anything noteworthy to my blog, but here we go. Let&amp;apos;s talk about something I&amp;apos;ve been cooking for a little over half a year now: the newest iteration of LÖVE Potion, 3.1.0. While it&amp;apos;s still not fully done, I did want to express the excitement of the new changes and mountain of fixes to the codebase that should make you excited as well. Seriously.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Fixes, Features, and a Little LÖVE</h1>
<p>Hello everyone, hope you're doing well! It's been a minute since I posted anything noteworthy to my blog, but here we go. Let's talk about something I've been cooking for a little over half a year now: the newest iteration of LÖVE Potion, 3.1.0. While it's still not fully done, I did want to express the excitement of the new changes and mountain of fixes to the codebase that should make <em>you</em> excited as well. Seriously.</p>
<h2> A Clean Slate</h2>
<p>Now, the first thing to mention is probably some context. Internally, all of LÖVE Potion's code has been overhauled <em>again</em>. Yes, again. The same reason that 3.0 exists as it currently does because <em>that</em> was its own rewrite. One could argue this should be considered 4.0, not 3.1.0, but the internal changes are really just stability™ and a few enhancements, nothing major.</p>
<p>Anyway, it all started when I had to do some bugfixes for 3.0 - and I think it was <a href="https://github.com/lovebrew/lovepotion/issues/226" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#226</a> and me trying to go through the codebase and find the correct <code>Source</code> object file. Even the user who posted the issue and made a PR had a tough time (including compilation and other things). See, in 3.0 I was advised with the brilliant idea of <em>templating</em> classes. Each class that required console-specific code would be templated and implemented from an enum which was decided at compile time. At first, this seemed like a genuine great idea, keeping the code separated and do platform-specific stuff as needed. Until it wasn't, because there was <em>so much code duplication</em> at some point. Hell, even writing out the templated stuff began to wear on me and become a massive chore.</p>
<p>I asked around the homebrew scene as to what I could do better. Someone (I believe TuxSH) had suggested using <a href="https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/language/crtp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Curiously Recurring Template Pattern</a> and it seemed to be a good solution. I got to work in a private repository to flesh things out and, for the most part, not a lot of things actually needed this pattern. Then the realization of not even needing it came and I just have regular Object-Oriented Programming and (pure) virtual methods.</p>
<p>Fast forward to today, almost everything from 3.0 is reimplemented and the codebase is <em>much</em> cleaner than before. This makes maintaining stuff so much easier.</p>
<h2> Testing Grounds</h2>
<p>One of the major things that I found out was that 3.0 had a lot of issues. Not like GitHub Issues, but actual code problems that I needed to fix. It was definitely more performant than 2.4, but we're talking things like expected versus actual results of function calls.</p>
<p>Luckily, user <a href="https://github.com/ellraiser" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ellraiser</a> had started making a LÖVE focused <a href="https://github.com/ellraiser/love-test" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">test suite</a> that ran all function calls to do exactly what I needed. It was an invaluable resource to validate the code I'd written so far and be absolutely sure things were exactly like the official version of LÖVE. One notable example was that <code>File:read()</code> had been incorrect and only pushed one of the return values to the Lua stack. It turned out that another function pushed multiple values, but I only pushed a single one.</p>
<p>The last time I ran the suite was on April 4, 2024. Most if not all tests that could run passed which was awesome. The tests did not run any graphics, audio, physics, or keyboard cases (simply because none of those modules were implemented yet). Prior to this day, there were some filesystem-related failures, which took me some time to debug, but ultimitely the baseline had been set once everything was running smoothly (except Wii U hashing stuff - blame it being big endian for that).</p>
<p>For those curious, here are the overall rankings of the top 3 functions that ran on each console (in the fastest console to slowest to finish)</p>
<ol>
<li>Nintendo Switch - <strong>1.122s</strong></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>love.thread.Channel: 0.204s</li>
<li>love.timer.getTime: 0.101s</li>
<li>love.timer.sleep: 0.101s</li>
</ul>
<ol start="2">
<li>Nintendo Wii U - <strong>2.470s</strong></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>love.sound.SoundData: 0.269s (<em>nice</em>)</li>
<li>love.filesystem.File: 0.225s</li>
<li>love.filesystem.getDirectoryItems: 0.226s</li>
</ul>
<ol start="3">
<li>Nintendo 3DS - <strong>5.105s</strong></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>love.sound.SoundData: 0.814s</li>
<li>love.filesystem.getDirectoryItems: 0.687s</li>
<li>love.filesystem.File: 0.499s</li>
</ul>
<h2> New Features</h2>
<h3> Remote Debugging</h3>
<p>This was a feature that was also backported to 3.0 (and inspired by similar homebrew tools and LÖVE for Android's use of adb) that allows a TCP socket to connect to your console and redirect all <code>print</code> calls from Lua back to your PC. It's super useful and has saved a lot of debugging time on my own end before getting the graphics API into the consoles, considering a Lua error ends up being <code>print</code>ed as well as displayed graphically based on the LÖVE code. It's as simple as enabling the <code>console</code> flag in <code>conf.lua</code> and using something like <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/administration/windows-commands/telnet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><code>telnet</code></a> or <a href="https://nmap.org/ncat/guide/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><code>netcat</code></a> to connect to the device IP on port 8000. When the flag is enabled, the console will wait for a connection up to 10 seconds before automatically resuming.</p>
<h3> Graphics API Changes &amp; Enhancements</h3>
<h4> Screen Dimensions</h4>
<p>While everything should be a near perfect replica of official LÖVE, users are aware that <code>love.graphics.getWidth</code>, <code>love.graphics.getHeight</code>, and <code>love.graphics.getDimensions</code> all take a string parameter that will then return the dimension(s) of that screen. This is now much more optional, as it will automatically fetch the screen information of what is currently being rendered and return it as appropriate. You can still request it manually (or it's planned at the very least if I haven't added it yet) for when you want a specific screen.</p>
<h4> The <code>love.draw</code> Callback</h4>
<p>Not too much of a noteworthy thing, but now <code>love.draw</code> will pass the current 3D slider value on Nintendo 3DS as a secondary parameter. This makes it a <em>lot</em> easier to draw stereoscopic 3D items on the screen.</p>
<h4> Better Batched Rendering</h4>
<p>LÖVE Potion 3.0 already had batched draw calls, but honestly it was awful. While it <em>sort of</em> batched draw calls (as in, more or less did), it used purely vertices and that took up a lot of memory, which especially on 3DS, we do not have a lot of. When I started working on the graphics API, I stared at the beast that LÖVE utilized for batched draw calls. I was terrified since it made no sense at all, but over time as I learned about how to use citro3d on 3DS I was able to figure it out. LÖVE uses a combination of a vertex buffer and index buffer which leads to reduced memory usage overall when drawing.</p>
<p>This gives the 3DS a massive performance boost when rendering (and a boost for the other consoles, but unsure how significant). How massive are we talking? Rendering a ton of text no longer lags the whole damn console. You can also render like 200 "points" (which are just circles and their radii calculated by point size) and still have 60FPS. I even did a test with <em>500</em> points and that dropped it to 40fps which is still insane <em>and that was technically 1,000 because it rendered to both screens</em>.</p>
<h4> Pure citro3d Backend</h4>
<p>A massive undertaking, to some degree. LÖVE Potion 3.0 for Nintendo 3DS currently uses <em>citro2d</em> which focuses only on the two-dimensional aspect of drawing. If I was going to make 3.1.0 worth the rewrite I absolutely had to use citro3d instead to give myself more flexibility and control. citro2d can only render certain primitives and fonts, but we had to match what LÖVE could do. Learning the API wasn't terrible, but I certainly did struggle getting the <code>StreamBuffer</code> class set up.</p>
<h2> Conclusion</h2>
<p>LÖVE Potion 3.1.0 is shaping up to be a massive leap forward in performance, usability, and features. While it’s not fully done yet, I’m thrilled about how far it has come and grateful for the support of the homebrew community. If you’re interested in testing, contributing, or just trying out the new features, stay tuned for the release or check out the GitHub repository! Let me know your thoughts — every bit of feedback helps make LÖVE Potion even better.</p>
<p>Thank you again to the following people who have supported and helped me: TuxSH, ellraiser, piepie62, mtheall, fincs, DeltaV, Nawias, the community for LÖVE, and the original inspiration to keep the project going all these years - Videah.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Post!</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-06-13-first-post.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-06-13-first-post.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">First Post!</source>
      <description>First Post! After looking over at the old website design, I decided that it was time for a more professional look. The old site wasn&amp;apos;t horrible, but it wasn&amp;apos;t exactly the best (especially functionally). Furthermore, I kind of wanted to get back into blogging if possible. I enjoy writing, hence the fact I&amp;apos;ve got a novel in the works. It should definitely motivate me to start working on it again. I never intended to stop working on it in the first place, of course. It&amp;apos;s just most of my time is being taken up by my job or just doing other personal projects. I&amp;apos;ll be taking a small-ish break from Love Potion, and this way I can hopefully work on my novel once more. The creativity of writing is just so enjoyable, and I don&amp;apos;t wish to abandon it--not yet at least.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> First Post!</h1>
<p>After looking over at the old website design, I decided that it was time for a more professional look. The old site wasn't horrible, but it wasn't exactly the best (especially functionally). Furthermore, I kind of wanted to get back into blogging if possible. I enjoy writing, hence the fact I've got a novel in the works. It should definitely motivate me to start working on it again.<br><br>
I never intended to stop working on it in the first place, of course. It's just most of my time is being taken up by my job or just doing other personal projects. I'll be taking a small-ish break from Love Potion, and this way I can hopefully work on my novel once more. The creativity of writing is just so enjoyable, and I don't wish to abandon it--not yet at least.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New State Of Mind</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-06-19-new-state-of-mind.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-06-19-new-state-of-mind.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">New State Of Mind</source>
      <description>New State Of Mind I figured I&amp;apos;d post about this since it&amp;apos;s something that&amp;apos;s rather important to me. I got a job back in November. They asked if I was alright with relocation, and I was. I still am. That&amp;apos;s the point of this post: I&amp;apos;m now in a different state. I previously lived in New jersey, a place that&amp;apos;s 300 miles from me now. I&amp;apos;m far away from my parents, and closer to one of my siblings.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> New State Of Mind</h1>
<p>I figured I'd post about this since it's something that's rather important to me. I got a job back in November. They asked if I was alright with relocation, and I was. I still am. That's the point of this post: I'm now in a different state. I previously lived in New jersey, a place that's 300 miles from me now. I'm far away from my parents, and closer to one of my siblings.</p>
<p>It's kind of bittersweet, really. I don't want to go into deep details, but it's kind of a relief and a involves a long healing process. I'm not a social person by nature, but honestly, I didn't want to deal with certain things back home. I'd get quite a bit of smack from my father.</p>
<p>Now I'm in Maryland far away from any possible issue with him. It's kind of hard to say I do miss him when I really feel like I shouldn't I'm just very conflicted as of late, since I've been thinking about it However, I think that in the remaining time here in my new place, he'll come to learn from his mistakes.</p>
<p>I'll be heading back home this weekend to get some of my stuff !couldn't take for this initial week, and I'm genuinely hoping for signs that he's gotten better towards me. Unfortunately, it might take more time than that, as my siblings left for months on their own accord only to come back for more important holidays as per our relgious beliefs or national holidays. My father treated them better once it had been months, but hopefully it doesn't take that long in my case.</p>
<p>Anyways, I'm enjoying my time here in Maryland. It's only been four days, but it's a very beautiful state, and home doesn't compare to it I've no idea what might happen when the year ends.. if my job brings me back to New jersey or if I can stay here. That's a discussion for myself in the future of course.</p>
<p>The adjustment to life in Maryland will take some time, but I'm open to this change, even if I was stressed as heck on arrival.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress Report</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-07-14-progress-report.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-07-14-progress-report.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Progress Report</source>
      <description>Progress Report It&amp;apos;s been about four weeks since the last post. Currently I&amp;apos;m renting an apartment which isn&amp;apos;t too far from where I&amp;apos;m supposed to work. I haven&amp;apos;t gotten much to do as of yet at the job, but it seems to be slowly picking up. I just don&amp;apos;t want to be too flooded with work, not that I&amp;apos;m complaining of course. Just enough to keep me busy and get through the days of the week.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Progress Report</h1>
<p>It's been about four weeks since the last post. Currently I'm renting an apartment which isn't too far from where I'm supposed to work. I haven't gotten much to do as of yet at the job, but it seems to be slowly picking up. I just don't want to be too flooded with work, not that I'm complaining of course. Just enough to keep me busy and get through the days of the week.</p>
<p>I haven't had time to do coding, but soon I'll be picking up my projects again. On the other hand, I did manage to write some more of my novel. I've been on chapter six for the longest time and I'm liking how it's coming along. Maybe I can finish this one up soon? I probably won't know for a while, but I am enjoying it thoroughly. I find the main issue with my novel is the length of chapters and the total amount I want to achieve. Average length of a chapter right now is probably five to six pages, and a dozen at most. The total amount of chapters is hopefully around twenty.</p>
<p>Having been here for only four weeks seems like forever now. I'm adjusting to living on my own and it's not as difficult as I'd thought. Anyway, that's about all I have for now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LÖVE-ly Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-10-04-lovely-upgrade.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2018-10-04-lovely-upgrade.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">LÖVE-ly Upgrade</source>
      <description>LÖVE-ly Upgrade Hardware Acceleration Finally after a long wait, GPU rendering support has come to Switch homebrew! If you&amp;apos;ve ever thought about making games on Switch, now is the best time. GPU rendering allows for better performance with OpenGL (or in the current situation for Löve Potion, SDL2 hardware acceleration).</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> LÖVE-ly Upgrade</h1>
<h2> Hardware Acceleration</h2>
<p>Finally after a long wait, GPU rendering support has come to Switch homebrew! If you've ever thought about making games on Switch, now is the best time. GPU rendering allows for better performance with OpenGL (or in the current situation for Löve Potion, SDL2 hardware acceleration).</p>
<h2> Call for Contributions</h2>
<p>There will also be a seperate branch which can be contributed to for OpenGL on the repository <a href="https://github.com/TurtleP/LovePotion/tree/gpu" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. Any help with getting the graphics ported from the original LÖVE framework to here will be greatly appreciated!</p>
<h2> Games</h2>
<p>Mentioned before, I look forward to people writing more games for homebrew on Switch with Löve Potion. If you make a project, please let me know and link its GitHub or <a href="http://itch.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">itch.io</a> to me on the repository or Discord.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squashing Bugs</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-03-15-squashing-bugs.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-03-15-squashing-bugs.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Squashing Bugs</source>
      <description>Squashing Bugs The last post I made was October and it&amp;apos;s definitely time for an update. For one, work has been keeping me rather busy the last few months. There were some minor worries here and there, but everything worked out. Secondly, things with my father have improved quite a bit. I know I spoke about that in the second post, where everything was rather downhill. However, I cannot stress enough that our relationship has improved.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Squashing Bugs</h1>
<p>The last post I made was October and it's definitely time for an update. For one, work has been keeping me rather busy the last few months. There were some minor worries here and there, but everything worked out.</p>
<p>Secondly, things with my father have improved quite a bit. I know I spoke about that <a href="https://turtlep.github.io/new-state-of-mind/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in the second post</a>, where everything was rather downhill. However, I cannot stress enough that our relationship has improved.</p>
<p>Third, progress on Löve Potion has taken a small hit. Granted it's due to work taking up most my time in the weekdays and I feel like relaxing once I'm home. I have merged both the 3DS and Switch code where applicable, and now it will be easier to have consecutive platform releases and fixes.</p>
<p>I also wanted to make this post about something that has been repeatedly bugging me. I don't know why, but it just feels like this one thing that happened with some old friends of mine has just come up time and again. I hate being reminded about it. I'm not against talking about <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/b0rb6m/what_was_the_tipping_point_of_your_last/eiibrsk/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=ios_app" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the events that took place</a>, but I would much rather forget about it all completely. These three individuals I had cared about--one of them I regret dating--and the other two, I genuinely wish the best for them. There's no reason that the other two people should really hate me, and the reason I <em>was</em> given was absolute garbage.</p>
<p>Anyways, I've just been trying to move onward from all of that. Forget about the past and move on. Sadly that's easier said than done, especially when you feel you've done nothing absolutely <em>harmful</em>, people hate you that you truly did care about, and the universe just kinda sits there flipping you off with these constant reminders of the subject every now and then.</p>
<p>The good news is that since all that happened I've met some amazing friends. People I can trust to talk to, those I care about. People who understand me. I'm glad I met you guys. I'll tag you all on Discord.</p>
<p>On top of that it had made me realize that my other friends, the ones I grew up with in high school and still talk to, are probably the best ones I can have, even if I am rather exhausted around them sometimes. They're amazing friends.</p>
<p>That's all I have for now, hopefully I can get to more posts, maybe once a month. No promises, but it would be nice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Story</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-04-16-writing-a-story.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-04-16-writing-a-story.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Writing a Story</source>
      <description>Writing a Story Something that&amp;apos;s come to mind as of recent is my novel. If you haven&amp;apos;t seen it yet, check it out. The overall progress has been rather slow, mostly because I tend to wind up with writer&amp;apos;s block. I&amp;apos;m trying to figure my way around it every time, and so far it&amp;apos;s just about taking a step back from the story and letting it simmer. Eventually, I do get back into the mood for writing, and usually it&amp;apos;s easy to be super eager and want to write an amazing idea down for the current chapter. I still don&amp;apos;t really know how long I want the book to be, but as of right now it&amp;apos;s 103 pages and 7 chapters. Granted that page count is due to the page size based on fiction novels which I chose the 6&amp;quot;x9&amp;quot; trim, as it seeems ideal for the design of the cover I want.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Writing a Story</h1>
<p>Something that's come to mind as of recent is my novel. If you haven't <a href="https://TurtleP.github.io/kingdomoferlain.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seen it yet, check it out</a>. The overall progress has been rather slow, mostly because I tend to wind up <a href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/dictionary/english/writer-s-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">with writer's block</a>. I'm trying to figure my way around it every time, and so far it's just about taking a step back from the story and letting it simmer. Eventually, I do get back into the mood for writing, and usually it's easy to be super eager and want to write an amazing idea down for the current chapter. I still don't really know how long I want the book to be, but as of right now it's 103 pages and 7 chapters. Granted that page count is due to <a href="https://www.millcitypress.net/author-learning-center/pod-trim-size" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the page size based on fiction novels</a> which I chose the 6"x9" trim, as it seeems ideal for the design of the cover I want.</p>
<p>One of the things I tend to do is really just let my writing flow naturally. Everything I've typed is practically improvised without a second thought. I've gone back to re-read parts of previous chapters, and it genuinely flows well. When it comes to editing, I don't usually go back and change things unless I think a specific part is rushed and needs more detail, something is out of place, or from feedback I get.</p>
<p>Another point I rely on is the story doesn't take itself too seriously all the time. There's obviously going to be bits of humor in books, but depending on the story it can be too serious, I think. Really though, this point is more about showing your characters actually <em>are</em> human. They do something stupid and something funny, awkward, or different than normal may happen. One example of this is in Chapter Two, <em>The Sorcerer</em> where in the middle of the chapter, the main character's curiosity gets to him and as a result, gets hit over the head by another character.</p>
<p>However, the hardest thing with writing a story is the concept of time. Sometimes you can get away with saying one scene happens in a few hours, but when time should shift to the next day or a couple of weeks--it just never seems like it works properly. It's about timing, I suppose.</p>
<p>Anyways, I might start sharing some favorite bits from the story in a few blog posts in the future. Not entirely sure if it'll be from <em>every</em> chapter, but be prepared for spoilers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making a Move</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-10-01-making-a-move.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2019-10-01-making-a-move.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Making a Move</source>
      <description>Making a Move It&amp;apos;s been a while and I figure right now would be a good time to post something. Even if it&amp;apos;s 8pm EST. I never really mentioned it, but I moved back home with my parents in New Jersey. It&amp;apos;s been about a month since I came back and I honestly regret it. I&amp;apos;d have hoped that many things would have changed once I moved back in, but for the better. They did at first which I was very surprised by. Unfortunately it didn&amp;apos;t last too long and there was a miscommunication and/or misunderstanding with dinner plans. My sister had my father and I talk it out and we came to a mutual understanding, one that would work for at most two weeks.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Making a Move</h1>
<p>It's been a while and I figure right now would be a good time to post something. Even if it's 8pm EST. I never really mentioned it, but I moved back home with my parents in New Jersey. It's been about a month since I came back and I honestly regret it.</p>
<p>I'd have hoped that many things would have changed once I moved back in, but for the better. They did at first which I was very surprised by. Unfortunately it didn't last too long and there was a miscommunication and/or misunderstanding with dinner plans. My sister had my father and I talk it out and we came to a mutual understanding, one that would work for at most two weeks.</p>
<h2> What Happened?</h2>
<p>During this time, I did follow through with things as necessary. Not like I was being forced, but I knew in the back of my mind that I just had to deal with it. I did my chores when they asked, which is genuinely all I asked of my parents to do for me. I'm not the best at keeping time, due to my ADHD, but it seemed to bug my father quite a bit that I didn't do things "on time". I expressed the issue with my ADHD interfering with doing stuff, as I've been off meds for almost seven years "under control" of it, but there's still a lack of understanding from him and my mother in regards to it.</p>
<p>The following weeks up until now have been kind of.. <em>depressing</em>, really. I've really never thought that it could be a possible issue until recently. I've been a bit frustrated with regards to work, but only slightly. Nothing major. The rest of it comes from the remaining weeks since about early-mid September. I don't want to dawdle and keep myself from telling everything, so here it goes: those weeks have just been brutal verbal abuse that I can't stand any longer.</p>
<p>It isn't exactly anything horrible, trust me. The worst thing that impacted me was him making snide comments, especially about "going back to my old ways" in which I wouldn't do things on time and just reside in my room all the time. I <strong>don't disagree</strong> that it occurred, so <em>why</em> am I so upset about it? It goes back to the original issue at hand: trying to keep myself sane while doing as I've been asked. I also happened to be getting involved with some of my hobbies again which rely use of my desktop in my bedroom.</p>
<p>I spoke to my siblings and they reassured me that they stand behind my decision to move out. Last Friday I went to a Starbucks and applied to an apartment. It's not too far from work just 5 minutes away in fact. A lot of good things can be said about where it is, but it doesn't matter in this context. I drove back home almost regretting the fact that I actually applied to it. Inside I was greeted by my father who was unusually calm about my late night (7pm EST versus 5:30/6:00pm EST) arrival. I turned on my desktop and couldn't connect to the internet at home. I figured it was odd. My suspicions were clear that he'd blocked (at least my phone and desktop) from accessing the WiFi (and I even texted him about it, and he admitted to it). I presume this was because he found out that I spoke to one of my friends briefly before he "banned" me from talking to them (over an apology said individual "owed" my mother. That's another story, but the whole thing was dumb because they were going to voluntarily apologize in the first place--and forceful apologies weren't an option for my friend in the sense of being entitled to one "because"). This issue only solidified my reasoning for the application.</p>
<h2> Bittersweet Closing</h2>
<p>I plan to tell my parents I've moved out once I settle in tomorrow. I don't think they'd somehow find this blog post (or my site anyways), but hey, if they did, I want them to know I love them, but deep down it hurts to write any of this. I'm sick of how I've been treated the past month and need not only time away from them, but my independence again. I need my mental health to be repaired from enduring the yelling and comments. I wish they understood what it feels like to be me, sitting in my room typing this out--having been frustrated with being treated poorly the past few weeks--although I tried that on Saturday, but neither of them were willing to listen or be understanding and it just sucks.</p>
<p>Anyways, on a cheerier note.. I was approved yesterday morning and I signed the lease today. I'm planning to move in tomorrow before my flight on Thursday for my brother's bachelor party.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The October Update</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2020-05-27-the-october-update.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2020-05-27-the-october-update.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">The October Update</source>
      <description>The October Update Once again, I&amp;apos;ve not written a post for a long, long time. Part of this is due to work, but another part of it is not having much to even write about. Today, I&amp;apos;m hoping I&amp;apos;ll change that starting next week with a higher frequency, specifically on Tuesdays. One other thing is I&amp;apos;ve updated the site a tiny bit. So there&amp;apos;s that. Oh, and if anyone reading this is interested in making homebrew games for Nintendo 3DS or Nintendo Switch, check out Löve Potion! I&amp;apos;ve been working on a complete overhaul that makes it way better on so many levels. The wiki link was updated in its page and even the wiki itself got some LÖVE! It now has a dark/light theme toggle and reflects the latest information about version 2!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> The October Update</h1>
<p>Once again, I've not written a post for a long, long time. Part of this is due to work, but another part of it is not having much to even write about. Today, I'm hoping I'll change that starting next week with a higher frequency, specifically on Tuesdays.</p>
<p>One other thing is I've updated the site <em>a tiny bit</em>. So there's that. Oh, and if anyone reading this is interested in making homebrew games for Nintendo 3DS or Nintendo Switch, check out Löve Potion! I've been working on a complete overhaul that makes it way better on so many levels. The wiki link was updated in its page and even the <em>wiki itself</em> got some LÖVE! It now has a dark/light theme toggle and reflects the latest information about version 2!</p>
<h2> The Long Answer</h2>
<p>When I made my post back in October 2019, I was certain on a few things. One of those was I wouldn't worry about my job shipping me to some other state in the U. S. The other half of it was me angrily, yet reluctantly getting out of my parent's house. The hope for the former--and it became both of them--eventually showed its ugly head.</p>
<p>The final day of December came by, the 31st. I was at work and a week or so prior my (project) boss informed me that I was going to be cut loose from my current project. I shrugged it off as I was given a notice and also the timeframe wasn't going to happen until about mid-January. He wanted to talk to me about the state of what was going on. Simply put that he did everything he could to have them keep me until the specified point in January, but it wasn't possible. I again thought nothing of it, though I was a bit discouraged. I was living by myself in an apartment that I paid for with my salary.</p>
<p>Luckily, however, it was just for the project. I was still going to get paid even though I was "on the bench" as it was put. Fantastic, and hopefully they'll find something for me soon--or so I thought. A month goes by and I'm informed about a position with <em>a new client</em> for my company. They wanted an interview with me and I was prepared with some questions they had allegedly informed the recruiter from my company with. I jotted down answers to the questions as referral material, nervously awaiting the day for this interview.</p>
<p>The day comes and I unfortunately <em>completely</em> screwed up. Part of that was because said client <strong><em>didn't even ask those questions</em></strong> and also because they threw what felt like nonsense at me. The main part of it was when they asked, "So what's your level of insurance knowledge" as if that makes sense. I tried to answer, but asked for clarification and the one guy that was there starts <em>describing what they do</em> such as underwriting and risk assessment. How does that even help me?! In the end, I obviously didn't get the position and I was excessively worried that I was going to be let go for that performance with a potentially new client.</p>
<p>When I spoke to the recruiters from my company, they were disappointed, but it wasn't as bad as I had thought. So that happened.</p>
<p>Four months go by and I'm trying to figure out what's going on with work. There were three other opportunities that came by, though they went out the window rather quickly, mostly because those presenting them didn't follow up properly. Eventually in late March, I get informed of a new client position. I was eager, but at the same time a bit reserved. I had to pay for the apartment I was in and my landlord had me under a rather tight contract. I couldn't break it under normal circumstances. The whole ordeal was that I had to move out and fly to Utah by the end of March and self-quaruntine for two weeks (this was of course the beginning of when COVID-19 was happening). There was a bit of push and shove, but nothing heavy. Because of this, I spoke to my landlord one final time about it. I cited that I was, well, threatened that I either keep my job or the apartment.</p>
<p>With that as the situation, I was told the property manager would let me break the lease for two month's rent and the lease breakage fee. Once that information was relayed properly to my work, I had to do the one thing I didn't want to: move back to my parent's place. I had nowhere else I could have gone, especially with the amount of stuff I had in the apartment.</p>
<p>That's pretty much the end of it all.</p>
<h3> The Good News</h3>
<p>Though it's a bit of a sour note for the prior section, it's really not all that bad. I genuinely have no idea why what happened.. happened last summer (and into the fall). My father and I saw someone to help with our understanding of one another and figure out this information. We really didn't figure it out, the only thing that <em>was</em> decided was how neither of us had ill intentions towards one another. Hard to really think that as the case when I would get ridiculed for some random, stupid stuff all the time, but okay I guess.</p>
<p>My father since I moved back in hasn't been as harsh. There were a few times where we did argue, again, over the <em>dumbest</em> of things. I actually forget the reason, but he eventually decided to block my WiFi connection because he got Google WiFi devices. Then he gave it back once I would do whatever he wanted me to do, such as when he did it because I was being a bit careless over cancelling my internet service at the old apartment. That was only because COVID-19 has caused long wait times and I had to call during a certain timeframe. Anyway, I don't really care because it's not hard to deal with. Recently he restored my phone's WiFi (yes that was also blocked) after I yelled at him. It had been maybe two months long.</p>
<h3> The Takeaway</h3>
<p>I really don't know if I have much for this part of the post, but I'm glad things are fine for the time being. I hope that they don't get as bad as they did last summer. I've been trying to better myself in different ways when it comes to my father's time-constrained needs (even though he's just impatient) by using timers on my Apple Watch to remind me when I need to do something. It's worked so far when I remember to set it, though I really do wish he wasn't so impatient about things.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runaway 2: Electric Boogaloo</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-03-23-runaway-two.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-03-23-runaway-two.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Runaway 2: Electric Boogaloo</source>
      <description>Runaway 2: Electric Boogaloo I wish that I did these blog posts more often, but it&amp;apos;s hard to get around to. I&amp;apos;ve mostly been busy with work and personal projects, which are some things I should actually try to write about on here. Maybe tomorrow or Thursday? Next Tuesday? Bring back Turtle Tuesdays (they were a thing ages ago on an old blogspot page I had).</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Runaway 2: Electric Boogaloo</h1>
<p>I wish that I did these blog posts more often, but it's hard to get around to. I've mostly been busy with work and personal projects, which are some things I should actually try to write about on here. Maybe tomorrow or Thursday? Next Tuesday? Bring back Turtle Tuesdays (they were a thing ages ago on an old blogspot page I had).</p>
<p>Anyhow, you might have stumbled across this random new post. Yes I've been inactive for almost a year now, but a lot of things have happened. I really do mean <em>a lot</em>. I mean in my personal life, not so much the general issue of COVID-19 overtaking our daily lives. So, what's with the title, you may ask? Great question!</p>
<p>That's what I would say, if it were a good thing. Though it is, it's been met with a lot of challenges.</p>
<h2> Story Time</h2>
<p>You see, since the post in May 2020, I once again realized that I shouldn't have come home again. Kind of a hindsight thing, but even at the time I felt unnerved about being back with my parents. I had been with them for almost 9 months and things were <em>okay</em>, but still not great. Though all of this is more about my father than my mother.</p>
<p>I stayed with them until one fateful day at the end of June.. or was it July? Either way, I had enough of putting up with my father. I couldn't do it anymore. That specific day he wanted me to do something, which I did and complained a bit, sure I'd admit. However, it wasn't called for when he started making remarks about extra work I had to do with the task at hand. He originally wanted me to pick up some branches from the driveway and then told me to snip their limbs off. His comments got worse and more annoying. So I gave up on the task and told him to do it if he didn't like how I was doing it. He threatened to cut off my internet access. Sure that shouldn't be a big deal right (Spoiler: it is*)? I got fed up and packed my car.</p>
<p>I packed it while my father brought my mother to work. Grabbed everything I could. My desktop, VR gear, clothing, anything else I thought was important or at risk. There came the point when I was about to leave and my mother came up to me. She told me because of what <em>I</em> had been doing, they were discussing divorce. I knew it was bullshit, but I also wasn't entirely sure. She'd threaten him many times during my childhood and it never happened. Still hasn't either.</p>
<p>Right before I got outside to my car, they stopped me in the garage. They essentially pleaded I stay. I could pay some rent and get unlimited internet access and not do chores. I straight up said it was not even worth it. I had enough. I left.</p>
<p>I told them I got a hotel, which was a lie. Went to tell my mother the truth at her job. I planned to go to Virginia. My friend had told me I could come stay with him and his family--which I'm not even kidding--was a bit stressful at times, but I can't even thank him enough for what he did. My mother got upset, called my father who said I could screw off and I just shrugged. I hugged my mother and at this point both of us were crying. I didn't really want to go, but I genuinely had to. Home wasn't a good place for me.</p>
<p>I wound up getting a talk from her coworker to ask my sister if I could stay with her. She said I yes, but only for a week. I had to look for apartments in the area. To keep that short, it came and went. I had to persuade her and my brother about going to Virginia. I couldn't find a place in Pennsylvania in time, even if she let me stay longer. There were a lot of.. concerns, though I managed to be confident in what I was doing. I made it to my buddy's place late that evening.</p>
<p>I stayed with my buddy for several months. It was genuinely.. difficult. Again still grateful as all hell for it, though. Unfortunately I had a few bad encounters with my parents during this time. I've mostly kept a good relationship with my mother, even if it is difficult due to my father. She at one point was mad because.. well.. she misinterpreted something my buddy texted her about not worrying about me and some other things.**</p>
<p>I can't forget when my father decided to <em>e-mail me</em>. I had blocked his phone number this entire time. He went off about being kicked off their health insurance effective January 1st and other things, like car insurance. Yeah it wasn't fun***.</p>
<p>Eventually, I got my own place. In fact, it's a condo. He was the one who found it. It's actually funny because it's right behind his place. Kind of funny--my mother wanted me to save up for one, although she also urged I stay in New Jersey. It's really nice with two bedrooms and bathrooms. Decent sized kitchen and living room. Mortgage -- at least compared to New Jersey (when I rented an apartment after leaving the <em>first time</em>) -- a lot cheaper. I'll have been here for about two months on the 28th. My parents don't even know, either.</p>
<p>* My main form of contact with a lot of my close friends are online. It wasn't even the first time he'd done it. He not only threatened, but even paused the connection. Also he "permanently" paused everything but my desktop. My raspberry pi, nintendo switch, nintendo 3ds, and probably other things. He was able to because of Google Mesh or whatever it is. I got around my desktop being paused with a MAC address changer. It was hilarious when he asked why there were multiples of my desktop name showing up. Everything else? Used the Hotspot feature on Windows 10 and connected them to it. <em>The future is now old man.png</em>.</p>
<p>**My father thought my friend would take advantage of my higher income status and I really think that's dumb. If anything I would offer to help them.</p>
<p>***I also have to do my taxes this year without any broker or whatnot to help. I was missing my bank student loan payment info and asked my mother to find it for me. This was because I thought they got it mailed to them, but it wasn't. I got it. Anyway, my father e-mailed me rather rudely about how I shouldn't be trying to use his broker person and I'm completely on my own. In turn I just wrote back, expressing the sheer amount of annoyance he brought. I wasn't even trying to do whatever he <em>thought</em> I was. I even said to not contact me ever again.</p>
<h2> Post Mortem</h2>
<p>Well not everything can be sunshine and rainbows. It sucks, really.</p>
<p>I wish I could say going to therapy would help, but I kind of gave up on it. I tried it for a while, but it just felt like an endless cycle of repeating myself to the therapist and getting nowhere. Though.. I could switch who I talk to. I just worry that once again I'll be talking and nothing will happen or come of it.</p>
<p>I tried to better myself in other ways like exercising, but through video games like Ring Fit Adventure. It kind of works, but I still lack the proper motivation and such to keep going.</p>
<p>I think the hardest thing for me right now though is work-related. I think that situation should be improving properly now, thankfully, but it's not as improved as I want it yet.</p>
<p>Looking back at it all--I was so stressed at home. I could tell because when I showered and washed my hair, it was falling out. If that's not stress-related then what is? I was also quite depressed. I can say it wasn't anything considered harmful, but I kept a lot of this stuff bottled up and in the back of my mind. I don't know how I even got myself through those days. I do believe, however, that perhaps someone else in my exact situation likely wouldn't have made it. I'd rather not think that way or about it, but.. I think it's a reality to look into.</p>
<p>Once again, I can't thank my friend enough for letting me stay with him. I was given an opportunity to leave Hell and I took it. Nobody else that I knew was even willing to let me stay with them, let alone as long as I had. We'll continue to be right next to one another with both good times and bad, I'm sure of it.</p>
<p>My mother.. I haven't spoken to her in a while since that thing with the taxes. I'm not sure how to approach her. My anxiety thinks my father said something to have her not talk to me, which is a possible situation, but hopefully not. I care about her and I do miss her. I wish she knew that, although she probably knows anyway.</p>
<p>My father? I've just really been trying to forget about him. It's kind of hard, but not in a good way of course. He's abused me emotionally and psychologically. While a lot of it could be considered minimal or stupid, I still can't forgive him for that. It's happened numerous times over the past four years, probably seven if I count the last three of University. In essence, it piles up and.. at this point it should make sense what I'm getting at.</p>
<h2> Next Up</h2>
<p>Come Tuesday, I think that I'll go over the progress of my novel and talk about LÖVE Potion a bit. I really want to talk about the latter in detail, but I dunno where to start. Maybe I'll do a Q&amp;A on the Discord to get started.</p>
<p>Until next time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fresh Start</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-04-06-a-fresh-start.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-04-06-a-fresh-start.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">A Fresh Start</source>
      <description>A Fresh Start So I figured that instead of doing this last Tuesday, why not start fresh next month? After all, it&amp;apos;ll give me some extra time between the posts to collect my thoughts. Aside from that, I figure that the first Tuesday of a month will be a post like this where I share information about something specific that I&amp;apos;m passionate about and then some kind of summary at the very last day of the month. Maybe I&amp;apos;ll add more posts between the two if I&amp;apos;m up to it, though. That&amp;apos;s at least the goal now.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> A Fresh Start</h1>
<p>So I figured that instead of doing this last Tuesday, why not start fresh next month? After all, it'll give me some extra time between the posts to collect my thoughts. Aside from that, I figure that the first Tuesday of a month will be a post like this where I share information about something <em>specific</em> that I'm passionate about and then some kind of summary at the very last day of the month. Maybe I'll add more posts between the two if I'm up to it, though. That's at least the goal now.</p>
<p>Anyways, today I'm going to talk about the novel revamp and how that's going.</p>
<h2> The Old Scrap</h2>
<h3> Comedy and Scenarios</h3>
<p>I'm not sure how many people even check my blog, or even the amount of people who do care about the fact I'm writing a novel. In either case, though, the point is that I've decided that it was best I start the whole thing over, save for some details. The reason that this was done is because the current story is.. okay at best I suppose? It was fine until I lost motivation again and then when I did pick it up, tried to modify the already existing data in the chapters. This really bothered me a lot because I'd look into what I could change to sound better or less "cheesy". Sometimes these things worked, but not all the time. It's fun that the novel didn't take itself seriously all the time and that's what I <em>absolutely</em> loved with it. However, too much of it can be a problem, like the following scenario:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>During Chapter 1, Serena and Esmund are going to the forest and Serena is pushing branches out the way and one of them snaps back, almost hitting Esmund behind her. She shouts how she's sorry for letting that happen and Esmund comments to himself how forgetful or clumsy she is. It's funny and quirky, but at the same time, felt a bit.. weird looking back at it now.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That scene of "comedy" was just a single example of this happening. Yes, funny, but it was overkill to some degree. There's multiples of these feelings when I reread it, which don't feel properly done and so as a result feels repetitive.</p>
<h3> Repetition</h3>
<p>Dear God, Speaking of repetitive things happening -- I think that was some of the worst things that bugged me. One thing that stands out the most as being repetitive is Esmund passing out. This happened like three times in the span of the first few chapters. He passes out in the forest, at the end of that same Chapter, and then nearly does in the middle of the one after it. I'm not sure if the ending of Chapter .. (4 or was it 5..?) counts, or even Chapter 3. It's got a weird vibe how it's done and I just don't like it <em>at all</em>. I would go into more detail about these events, but it's a bit difficult to do since there's no actual way to present spoilers in Markdown.</p>
<h3> Storyline</h3>
<p>This is probably the least of the problems with the old content. I don't necessarily hate the way the plot is or anything, but realistically the way certain events happen bugs me. One thing for sure is the first Chapter ended. The simple way of how it ends, which what I had is the idea, was not the proper execution. It again had that problem of feeling weirdly done because of verbiage and it came out awkward or corny.</p>
<p>Another issue was not having enough backstory for the Prologue as well. That was something I always debated whether it was good or not. It was a mere few pages long, but it did set the tone and world up nicely. I just had the feeling I should have expanded on it instead of having it the way it was. However, I'll go into more detail in a bit.</p>
<h2> New Overview</h2>
<p>I don't think I can really tell as much information as I'd like at the moment in the same way for the old cruft. However, I do think that I can safely say that scenarios are less awkward and can be more of an appropriate serious tone.</p>
<p>Even the Prologue itself got the extension it deserved. The original is nice, but the new one hit a bit harder. It develops the plot even more by giving the reader the background on the character in the first place.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sure a mysterious person in a forest is cool and thought provoking, but <em>why</em> are they there? It's addressed many Chapters later in the old version, but.. now it makes more sense: once for the reader and then again for the actual characters involved meeting this particular Prologue character later on.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chapter 1 is the farthest I've gone so far, though. It was a bit of a struggle to start, but I think I got past that rather quickly. I mainly wanted to change up how interactions between Esmund and Serena were. Make them more human-like and less goofy or overly dramatic.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The scene where Esmund and Serena are eating breakfast in the morning has changed quite a bit. The conversation always felt rather awkward, even with a serious tone added to it. I tried this time around to make it more of what that interaction should have been. They feel more like the kind of interaction I'd expect from siblings that are close with one another. There's no arguing or such, just building the dynamics of their relationship in a better way than before.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The idea of Chapter 1's ending is still something I liked, even though it was definitely not the best laid-out. Having Esmund pass out and then realize he should go back home was a rather rushed concept. I think that this time around everything will just be going from the house to the forest, adding some.. interactivity there, and then end of the Chapter. I've got plans to change up the next Chapter (2) as well since everything will mostly happen in the forest in Chapter 1. Adjustments are always necessary to make it less clumped together, I think.</p>
<h2> End Notes</h2>
<p>Well, I tried to give a nice detailed view about the work so far without being too vague about some stuff. Just trying to avoid spoilers, really. I look forward to finishing the first Chapter and then publishing it on the proper section on the Blog.</p>
<p>I think that the next post I make will be about LÖVE Potion. I still need to get some kind of Q&amp;A session going about that on the Discord server. That or figure out what to start talking about.</p>
<ul>
<li>TurtleP</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Trouble of Sleep</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-10-12-the-trouble-of-sleep.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2021-10-12-the-trouble-of-sleep.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">The Trouble of Sleep</source>
      <description>The Trouble of Sleep Well, to start I need to update my status about how things are going overall. I did kind of promise to do more &amp;quot;Turtle Tuesday&amp;quot; type things and summarize the month at the end. That&amp;apos;s clearly going well. Jokes aside, however, I&amp;apos;m doing fine. I got to see some of my university friends back in July for a quick visit. That was fun. I also got to see my friends from high school. Though really, the best part was being able to see my mother.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> The Trouble of Sleep</h1>
<p>Well, to start I need to update my status about how things are going overall. I did kind of promise to do more "Turtle Tuesday" type things and summarize the month at the end. That's clearly going well.</p>
<p>Jokes aside, however, I'm doing fine. I got to see some of my university friends back in July for a quick visit. That was fun. I also got to see my friends from high school. Though really, the best part was being able to see my mother.</p>
<p>It was definitely a tough thing to do. It had been months and I rarely communicate with her. However, I had asked her to be sure as to whether or not I would be allowed to see her at her job. She allowed it and needless to say, it went well. Kind of.</p>
<p>For starters, I asked if she was in the pharmacy (as she is a pharmacist). I was asked if I was her son, and agreed of course. She opened the door and I just couldn't help but cry. I missed her a lot. Probably more than I even realized and she knew it, she missed me too.</p>
<p>We had a discussion regarding me coming back home to New Jersey, although.. I had to tell her I couldn't. Pretty sure I mentioned last post how I have my own place now and all that jazz. So I had to tell her. She pleaded a bit, but I had to straight up tell her that I am mortgaging this place and it's not rented. I had to find my own place as per my father's wishes, so.. yeah. She also wanted me to have dinner with my father, but I tried my best to be polite and decline because I'm keeping his supposed rules in place, That bridge has already been burnt and there's zero percent chance of repair, honestly. He was also not feeling well or sick, so that was another reason to not bother.</p>
<p>The last thing I want to probably briefly touch on, but not explicitly talk of.. because I'm uncertain about it. I've been thinking about certain things of late and probably not comfortable about talking to specific people about it yet. I think the biggest issue for that is mainly about whether or not I fully agree with the idea. I've been trying to try things regarding it, but it's a mixed bag in a way. Plus trying to talk to my siblings and such about it would definitely not be my priority as my anxiety would not like that. It never would with anyone regarding this.</p>
<h2> The Sleep Stuff</h2>
<h3> Background</h3>
<p>You know, this is the most god damn annoying thing that keeps happening to me. These, as I call them, "sleep seizures". I can't confirm if that's what they are, either and my current neurologist doesn't/didn't believe me about it. So this part serves as an explanation and gives some context.</p>
<p>Back in roughly 2016 or 2017 I began to notice something weird with my sleep patterns. I didn't think about it all that much and as a result likely just thought nothing of it. However, as time went on these became more of a semi-frequent issue. All I knew was that I would wake up <em>exhausted</em> and felt a bit horrible, at least mentally. Like I said already, I had tried on several occasions to tell my neurologist, ask on Reddit if applicable (on something like r/epilepsy), but never got any answers.</p>
<p>Eventually, I had figured something out to the issue and when it would happen. This is where the pretty scary stuff comes in. I hate it so much, but I have no idea if there's anything I can do to either diagnose it or anything.</p>
<h3> What is It?</h3>
<p>Then I would fall asleep, right? You lie down in bed and just knock out. Except.. we're gonna go on a bit of a slope. Please note that I am basing all of this on my epilepsy as the root issue. However, I also <strong>do not</strong> fully know if it is the cause.</p>
<p>My epilepsy consists of nothing but a short burst in the frontal lobe are of the brain. If I'm not mistaken, in English, that's just the front of the top of your head area. They are <em>quick</em> like a lightning strike, but they trail off just as easily.</p>
<p>Now, when it comes to falling asleep, it's a bit different. I'd still get that feeling where something is happening to the front of my head, but it doesn't seem to go away. This causes me to fall asleep during the episode and leave this.. buzzing sensation going on for some time. It also leaves me in a half-awake type of state in the sense that while asleep, I am fully aware that I am asleep. It's kind of confusing, but trust me it makes sense if you think about it a bit.</p>
<p>Once half-awake or whatever you might call this, I can actually <em>think</em> what I want, Majority of the time it's legit, "ah shit here we go again" and "I need to wake up".</p>
<p>Quick recap: epileptic seizure going on, lucid awake(?), and able to think properly. No, I am not dreaming this all up.</p>
<p>When I manage to wake up, I have a chance of entering a state of sleep paralysis. This isn't any fun either because it's a 50/50 on me actually being <em>awake</em> as in eyes open. Hell, I don't know if they do open, but since it's usually night time when this happens I can't see a single thing and it's pitch black in the room. During this time of suspended.. time I either fully snap out of it or I have to scare myself awake with something. Just imagining some creepypasta-based stuff is good enough for me, though sometimes it hasn't worked and it takes a bit longer to get out of.</p>
<p>In the end of the sleep paralysis (or lack thereof) I wake to find myself extremely exhausted, more mentally than physically. My movements are sluggish, my brain has no thoughts and I refuse to return to sleep. Though, another thing: sometimes my body decides I haven't had <em>enough</em> and I fall back asleep almost immediately--and once more I have potential to run the cycle.</p>
<h3> Sleep Apnea</h3>
<p>One of the things I foud out about two years ago is that I do in fact have sleep apnea. I won't go into details, but basically you have issues breathing in your sleep. There's different reasons per person.</p>
<p>I do have treatment for this and I make use of the machine nightly to ensure I get a proper night's sleep. However, this only came about because I would wake up tired as hell for work. Didn't look good if I were to fall asleep during work either, but even if that did happen <em>cough</em> it was medical reasoning and at the time I couldn't do anything about it.</p>
<h3> Hypothesis or Whatever</h3>
<p>See, the thing is that sleep apnea is supposed to prevent issues while <em>breathing</em> during sleep. Epilepsy <em>can</em> be triggered via things like shortness of breath, for example. I recall doing <a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/treatment-tests-and-therapies/electroencephalogram-eeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">EEG tests</a> where they would have  me purposely emulate hyperventalation. It wouldn't exactly set mine off, although I would get light headed. I might have just been bad at doing it though, who knows.</p>
<p>This leaves me with the idea that the sleep apnea may be causing the epilepsy--which it itself might have its own subcategory when I sleep. I've looked into these before, but neither make much sense to me. Specifically <a href="https://www.epilepsy.com/learn/types-seizures/tonic-clonic-seizures" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tonic-clonic seizures</a> or <a href="https://www.epilepsy.com/learn/types-seizures/myoclonic-seizures" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">myoclonic seizures</a>. Although interestingly, there are <a href="https://www.epilepsy.com/learn/types-epilepsy-syndromes/progressive-myoclonic-epilepsies" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">progressive myoclonic epilepsies</a>. These do sound a bit more accurate, but my main concern is about <em>time</em>.</p>
<p>I often try to know what time I fall sleep for the night in the event this happens. The reason being is that tonic-clonic seizures are.. well, deadly. Apparently these should only last from one to five minutes and anything longer should be a 911 call. I find myself waking up from these for a much longer duration than that. For example, last night I had an episode that lasted from 00:17 until 00:57. Although there was a break between them even if it was brief. So while that is fourty minutes, it might have been about two twenty minute ones.</p>
<p>Needless to say, I don't know if I'll get a proper diagnosis about this anytime soon and it sucks. If my  sleep episodes are at all related to my epilepsy, the best I can probably do is keep taking my mediccation. Even that, however, doesn't always prevent it. Nothing's ever entirely preventable I guess, but as long as you can do something to prolong an issue from happening, it's worth it.</p>
<h3> Stories</h3>
<p>I know this is getting lengthy, but this last part might be optional to a lot of you unless you want to be spooked. I hate recalling these scenarios, but it's whatever.</p>
<h4> One</h4>
<p>There was this time when I still worked for Sonic back in probably 2016 when this started or partway through, dunno. At the time I was waiting for my bed frame to be replaced because my parents were going to get rid of the old one I had and so I had to sleep on the mattress on the floor. That afternoon I had to work, but was tired, so I went to take a nap. I climbed onto the mattress and shortly after fell asleep, but I also had one of these episodes. Part of what I mentioned was me trying to wake up.. well some scary stuff is that given it was light out and I was trying to wake up from it, I saw one of my hand just kind of spasming in place, so that wasn't traumatizing or anything, nope.</p>
<h4> Two</h4>
<p>I often recount this one as a big issue for me because I think it contributed to memory loss of <em>some kind</em>. The breakdown is this: I fall asleep, problem happens as usual, but I woke up in a dream. I dreamt that I sat up in my bed, although I couldn't see anything. I was exhausted as usual and just went back to sleep only to then wake up under the kitchen table with my blankets on me. I was highly confused, still couldn't see, but slept once more. I finally woke up in the dream once more to me trying to make my way to my parent's bedroom and tried to speak and shout to them for help since I still couldn't see a thing. I fell. Then the darkneess overtook me once more and there was some kind of ring formation made from cloth. It pulsated and eventually began to shrink and something felt really off. It got so small and right before anything else happened I actually woke up this time. I gasped for air, unable to think or remember anything for roughly 15 seconds. It felt like a lot longer at the time, though.</p>
<p>I couldn't remember where I was, who I was, nothing. For that whole small duration. I did slowly remember things afterwards and started with the basics. What's even more creepy is probably the fact I didn't remember needing to go to work and my body <em>just did</em>. I got in uniform, to the car, and drove. Didn't know where I actually was or anything, but knew I had to go to work for some odd reason. I did realize after a bit when I was nearly at work where I was, but it's still weird.</p>
<h4> Three</h4>
<p>This is the last one that I remember. Much like the first story, fall asleep, etc. Except my right leg was raised and I don't really know how I knew at first. My head was buzzing like crazy and I figured I should put my leg down since it shouldn't be like that. This was a mistake. Moving my leg even the slightest bit made that buzzing sensation even worse. I don't even recall how I woke up from that one.</p>
<p>There's also the time where both my legs were just kicking in the air (again this is something I could feel through my brain). Which that was weird.</p>
<h2> Conclusion</h2>
<p>Long post, but worth it. I needed a way to firmly document this somewhere and not just on my phone, for example. Maybe someone will stumble across this and help, I dunno.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things On My Mind</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2022-05-02-things-on-my-mind.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2022-05-02-things-on-my-mind.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Things On My Mind</source>
      <description>Things On My Mind Well, it&amp;apos;s been about seven months since I last posted anything on the blog. I think it&amp;apos;s time for another update. Unfortunately some bad things have happened, but some good comes from it. I&amp;apos;ve been mostly holding out on this because I don&amp;apos;t want people to see my blog, read a bunch of negativity, and then be like, &amp;quot;Oh they do nothing but post negative stuff all the time!&amp;quot; Yet you, the reader, may then catch yourself, &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;d not think that about this!&amp;quot; Hopefully people are more of the latter. The blog posts have been something of a space where I can speak my mind. A place to pour what I feel into words where I typically fall short most of the time. If that happens to be a lot of these posts, so be it. Anyhow, onto the updates.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Things On My Mind</h1>
<p>Well, it's been about seven months since I last posted anything on the blog. I think it's time for another <em>update</em>. Unfortunately some bad things have happened, but some good comes from it. I've been mostly holding out on this because I don't want people to see my blog, read a bunch of negativity, and then be like, "Oh they do nothing but post negative stuff all the time!" Yet you, the reader, may then catch yourself, "I'd not think that about this!" Hopefully people are more of the latter. The blog posts have been something of a space where I can speak my mind. A place to pour what I feel into words where I typically fall short most of the time. If that happens to be a lot of these posts, so be it. Anyhow, onto the updates.</p>
<h2> October 2021</h2>
<p>Several months ago was the last time I posted. Yet that was also the last time I spoke to one of my friends whom I met through VRChat. There's a whole god damn rabbit hole about why, <a href="https://t.co/BiP2HAYJYH" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">particularly from my other friend's Twitlonger</a>. Though I haven't spoken much about it, at least publically. On my side of things, all I did and wanted was to care about a friend, but they seemed to take advantage of it.</p>
<p>In post-mortem fashion, I've found that they were just a manipulative person and it absolutely sucks. The constant attention-seeking attitude they have and how easily they can lash out at another person was horrifying, to say the least. I had tried to help them with their problem of being attached to people <em>frequently</em> and yet all I got was a blank affirmation. To clarify, essentially going in and out of relationships as short as a week and as long as a few months, only to then find someone else shortly thereafter. I care about my friends and every breakup they had I would be there for them. Again, unfortunately, I had been playing into their hands. In the end, they got back with an ex of theirs (who they themselves <em>complained</em> to <em>me</em> about). When I asked why (and told them it was a bad idea, which could be argued as wrong to do, but I don't think it was) they agreed, told me it wouldn't last and tried to act like it would be fine. This was the last straw for them. I'd already grown tired of consoling them multiple times and severed the friendship.</p>
<p>Since then, I've realized all the things they had said to me was just fodder. They called me their "bestie". When I first heard that from them, it felt completely empty with no emotion at all behind it as if it were a mere label to just slap and give anyone. They claimed they care about their friends, yet all they seem to do is either shove Twitch bits at them (as most of them stream) or completely collapse and remove everyone from being friends and ignoring them. Don't get me wrong, I understand what it feels like to be depressed, they had mentioned to me personally that they <em>are</em>. However, it still does not justify things at all. Regarding the Twitch thing, it feels like it's genuinely just a way to keep these other people happy and not leave said person's side. I doubt that many of them actually think that way, but from an outside perspective that's what it looks like.</p>
<p>Of course, I can't forget the fact of how dumb and childish it was once I had unfriended them. It ended nicely, or so I thought. I found out the next day that my other friend, Jay, had been banned from their Twitch chat (I don't know if it's still the case, but it doesn't justify anything anyway if they are not). Subsequently, I checked and I was too. They even blocked me on Discord (presumably, though a status such as "true friends don't unfriend me, if they do I block them" kind of states the obvious here).</p>
<h2> Late November/December 2021</h2>
<p>This one is a bit of a pain to talk about. Particularly because there's a particular bunch of people who think they understand things and decide to phrase words as though they know what they mean. If you're that person who I'm talking about, I want you to genuinely read through this section. I'm going to be putting all the thoughts about this on paper (virtually). This is not a matter of who is right or wrong. It's not about making people look bad. If telling the events and facts of the story make that person look "in the wrong" or whatever because of their actions.. well.. ¯_(ツ)_/¯</p>
<p>If you read <a href="https://turtlep.github.io/2021/03/23/run-away-part-2.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this post from last March</a> then congrats, you have context. If not, eh, you probably won't entirely need it. The "tl;dr" is I had once more had enough of dealing with my father and "moved in" with a friend (who I shall denote as "Friend A" or "A" for short) who lives in Virgina. I eventually got my own place in January 2021, which is really nice.</p>
<p>This is the story of more stupidity than is necessary. There's a bit more context, so I'll be jumping around in time a bit here.</p>
<h3> The Intro</h3>
<p>I began to stream on Twitch (again) in July of 2021 after a long hiatus of not having anything to stream. In July, though, I wound up streaming actual games instead of live coding. I'd stream playing VRChat, Tomb Raider, or whatever else is on my Steam library. IT's fun and gives me something to look forward to during the week. Multiple times, before I had gotten my new place (and even when I did have it), my friend would need to go to the store to buy stuff for dinner or just get me out of the house. It's not the worst thing in the world. If the time overlapped with streaming, I'd merely have to cancel that night and wait for the next time I'd stream.</p>
<p>So, finally landing here in December 2021. Friend A and I went out early in the day to go to the hardwood store so he could fix his couch. I bought dinner after we finished that trip, dropped him off at home, and then went back home myself and then went to eat dinner.</p>
<h3> The Argument</h3>
<p>Shortly after, Two of my friends (let's say B and C) wanted to play Phasmophobia (which is a pretty fun game if you haven't heard of or played it). I was scheduled to stream that night, so I figured why not ask if I might be able to stream it? They were up for it, which was all cool. Meanwhile, Friend A decided to poke me really quickly on Telegram (or via Discord? Text message? I can't recall, especially text message as I don't have that phone anymore since I changed carries that month). He was asking, "Hey could you come over to test the couch?" I replied that I could, should I have time left before I streamed that night, which was in 30 minutes.</p>
<p>A few minutes (I think around 10) passed; I was still in the middle of eating. I recall thinking, "Well, wait, why do I have to help test this? His kid is the one who broke [the couch]." I messaged him asking this. Some more minutes pass and the response was, "It has to be you," if memory serves. This confused me, so I again asked, "Though your kid was the one who broke it. If you can't have him sit on it, why not the other one?". The reply was, "The other kid is too lightweight to even do anything to the couch <em>and it requires two people</em>." (emphasis mine). Deeply confused, I pressed again, "What about you and your wife? Both of you are clearly grown adults who could sit on this couch to test it." I was waiting for a reply, and I can't recall if I got one, but it was probably, "It has to be you." Regardless, it was now I believe 7:45 after some waiting. I messaged them saying, "Well, whatever, if I have time after I finish eating, I'll help you."</p>
<p>Stream time came, 8:00pm EST. I had just finished my dinner a few minutes prior and typically when I start, I do it 5 minutes before, so 7:55pm. This is purely a waiting buffer to have people join before I actually start. Friends B, C, and myself all hopped into the Discord voice chat as we started to play Phasmophobia. About 30 minutes later, Friend A pings me, "This doesn't look like streaming" with a photo of me in voice chat with the other two. I replied, "If you look up in the conversation histroy, I asked to stream Phasmophobia with them and this is how we play the game."¹ Once that interaction with Friend A ended, I felt a bit uneasy, but that's because I don't usually like confronting people unless I really feel it's necessary.</p>
<p>Since that happened, the following days and weeks of me trying to talk to them were awkward. I was essentially chatting <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/talking-to-brick-wall" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">with a brick wall, much like how this meme shows</a>. I decided at one point to just leave Friend A alone for a few weeks.</p>
<h3> An Alternate Route</h3>
<p>I went out shopping one day and finally decided to check up on them. Initially I tried to message as if everything was okay, like nothing happened, but I was once again met with no responses at all. I even asked, "Is this about me not helping with your couch?" and got nothing. Thus, I had to make <em>some</em> decision on what to do.</p>
<p>Once I got home and settled down, I messaged his wife. I checked in with her, since I wanted to make sure they were okay since their youngest's class was exposed to covid. She told me everything was fine, they were just stuck in quaruntine and it "was kind of hell" (my words, but accurate). I then asked her about why Friend A was not answering my messages, what I could have possibly done wrong.</p>
<p>I got a message stating he was still mad about the couch situation and I was annoyed. I don't remember if I said anything, but I do recall that she expressed her annoyance with him being mad about the couch and she was also mad about it. This is going to be paraphrased, but: she told me that the whole thing was stupid and I should have just helped regardless and canceled the stream because "you only get like two viewers." She then further noted that, "when you [TurtleP] want something done, it has to be immediately done, but if he [Friend A] wants something done, it has to wait." That was not true. I then requested to get my spare house and car keys back, as I felt like I couldn't trust Friend A at that moment with all the tension going on.</p>
<p>There had been multiple times where either of us wanted something done, but the other said it would have to wait. There have been times where either of us have basically forced the other to do something when they wanted it done. For example, on days when I didn't feel like doing <em>anything</em>, Friend A would <em>force me out of the house</em> even though I didn't want that.</p>
<p>It particularly bothered me that I was basically being told how I was a shitty person for not doing something I was asked (even though I didn't guarantee it).</p>
<p>I'd done a lot for them while I stayed with them, which I reminded her of several things. Somehow, later that afternoon when Friend A found out about that, he pinged me in Discord (which I left that server after that because I didn't want to deal with drama). I found out from a friend who was there, from a screenshot, that Friend A <em>thought I was complaining about the things I reminded his wife of, that I had done for them</em> and decided to refute all the points I made. Which makes.. zero sense.</p>
<p>Knowing he did this <em>in public</em> instead of <em>in private</em> also pissed me off quite a bit. This was something between us, why bring it in where <em>everyone else</em> can read it? It serves no purpose other than <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcYG-5b7448" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">spilling beans (or chili in this case)</a> everywhere to "look better," especially with how it was handled.</p>
<h3> Confusion &amp; Annoyance</h3>
<p>Another few weeks went by, and another friend was asking me to rejoin the Discord server in a semi-public server chat. I wasn't sure about it. I felt uneasy and it would be awkward. Then the topic of the situation came up, to which Friend A jumps in and says.. whatever they said and someone legit had to tell Friend A off and take it to direct messages because it wasn't for public consumption.</p>
<p>That conversation happened, which was a wild fucking ride, let me tell you. Imagine knowing someone for two years. They know all the bad shit that's happened. Suddenly they act like you've lied about all of that as if trying "to play victim." Yeah, I was being told that I wanted to play victim here and get everyone on my side, which.. never was the point?²</p>
<p>Yet, when I finally rejoined that Discord server, I didn't know how to feel except nervous. I didn't expect to be pinged by Friend A at all. Every time they did, I just didn't answer because I wasn't sure how to reply. I also did want them to talk to me about the whole argument thing and come to good terms, if possible, but that wasn't going to happen either. Some weeks later, people ask why I'm not replying and then Friend A thinks I'm being petty. I don't get it myself, but whatever. I had to reply at this point and explain why I've been not replying. I get faced with responses about why it was bullshit and it made my feelings about the whole thing invalid.</p>
<p>Eventually there comes a day where I was trying to ping Friend A. I got no reply, but thought nothing of it. I continued to do whatever I was doing elsewhere. Then another couple of days go by. I was in my friends list on Discord reading some messages with people and scrolled by Friend A. Out of curiosity, I right clicked their profile and it said "Add Friend". This was essentially the final straw and I left the server once more.</p>
<p>In that conversation when I first rejoined, Friend A made claims about not wanting to "rekindle a friendship" and how "he doesn't care about {whatever}". Yet he'd post a message in a Telegram group chat we share, <em>very obvious</em> things that had to do with me. One being the new green iPhone 13 that came out, or even a link about Sleep Apnea stuff. You could argue that it could have been anyone, but I have high doubts.</p>
<h3> Conclusion</h3>
<p>In conclusion, yes, this whole thing <em>is completely stupid</em>. Like I mentioned before the whole story, this isn't about who's right or wrong. This is about detailing the events of what happened as factual, not opinion. It is wholly up to you as the reader to decide what to make of it. This isn't some kind of "petty move" either, so please don't utter those words.</p>
<p>I also don't know if one person³ in particular was speaking on behalf of Friend A regarding them not replying when I pinged them the one time, but they aren't a mind reader, so if that's what Friend A had said, and quote, "He didn't respond to pings because you have a "do not engage" message pretty clearly" I find that stupid. If I did have that, I would have made it more obvious, I think. Even if I didn't Friend A acted like nothing happened once I had returned, invalidated my feelings, and then things went "back to normal" from there. That is to say, we actually chatted like normal, even though I didn't like that.</p>
<hr>
<p>¹Granted this is a bit backwards, but it was for when someone died in-game. You can't hear others talking when they've died. Sure, it spoils the game a bit when someone can unmute and then say "oh yeah the ghost spawned over at {location}", but whatever. Not the point.</p>
<p>²Their claim was purely based on the fact that I "left out" some key information about why he was mad. The only thing I left out (which was on accident; but I also didn't think was even important) was about him asking me to help <em>before</em> streaming.</p>
<p>³If said friend is reading this, stop trying to be a mind reader and stop throwing words (e.g. calling me petty) around like this. I get trying to think about it from an outside perspective, but the more I've tried to understand what you say, the more it feels like it's just what Friend A said and not someone else. If the other people in that Discord server that we're both friends with are in agreement about this statement, show me proof, but even then, I think they're plain wrong.</p>
<h2> Present</h2>
<p>Now that all of that's out of the way, some better things to talk about. Soon, on the weekend of the 14th, is my sister's wedding. I'm quite excited for it, even if I can't express that properly. I've got my suit ready and hopefully it'll be a good time. Supposedly our father isn't going to the wedding now (family-related drama because he's a god damn child), so maybe I won't need to see him there. Whether he's there or not, I think I'll be able to manage.</p>
<p>Streaming on Twitch has become quite fun. There's some times where I feel like I can't keep going, of course. Though that's because the chat doesn't really.. engage. I might have like two or three people, but only one of them speaking. It's a whole process. I try to make the most of it, though, because I want to do it for fun and knock off games that I want to play from my Steam library.</p>
<p>I've also made a slight bit of progress on my novel, so there's that. Nothing significant, but it is progress at least.</p>
<p>Overall, though, I'm a lot happier, I guess. I've met awesome people who support me and do care about me, though the term "Best Friend" will scar me for some time. I've decided that if someone tries to call me such (or variants (and seriously)) that I will punch them in the throat (not really, but still).</p>
<p>I do, however, want to make note of the people that I've met the past few months (and I guess years?) who I think really do care about me and I care about them (in no particular order):</p>
<ul>
<li>jjsvqz</li>
<li>weird0_lover</li>
<li>Kallisata</li>
<li>*anime_noises*</li>
<li>StaringOnly</li>
<li>lexvi</li>
<li>Dax</li>
<li>Crumbsy</li>
<li>Uzume</li>
<li>Umi</li>
<li>AuroraTears</li>
<li>Zack1118vc</li>
<li>Emaki</li>
<li>Phazonic Ridley</li>
<li>Glazed Belmont (aka Glazy)</li>
<li>xnoe</li>
<li>Garuma</li>
<li>Jay_Saw</li>
<li>Cryptic</li>
<li>Zacyntho</li>
<li>Blannk (aka Bob)</li>
<li>Jman (aka Predster)</li>
<li>piepie62</li>
<li>emymin</li>
<li>Power</li>
<li>Tyto</li>
<li>GiantTrailBiker</li>
<li>Oatmeal_Addict</li>
<li>Wolfgang Fangs</li>
<li>Percy_creates (aka Percy)</li>
<li>AFS (aka KIP)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good News, Everyone!</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2022-12-18-the-almost-good-news.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2022-12-18-the-almost-good-news.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Good News, Everyone!</source>
      <description>Good News, Everyone! Intro Long time no posting.. It&amp;apos;s been uh, almost seven months since the last blog post. I think it&amp;apos;s been long enough that it warrants an update from me. It&amp;apos;s pretty hard to remember that I have a blog sometimes, and even when I do, find something to write about. Especially trying to not make a lot of the updates about negative things So, let&amp;apos;s get started with what&amp;apos;s what.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Good News, Everyone!</h1>
<h2> Intro</h2>
<p>Long time no posting.. It's been uh, almost seven months since the last blog post. I think it's been long enough that it warrants an update from me. It's pretty hard to remember that I have a blog sometimes, and even when I do, find something to write about. Especially trying to not make a lot of the updates about negative things So, let's get started with what's what.</p>
<h2> Streaming</h2>
<p>I used to go by the name "TurtleP95" on Twitch, although I switched that around once I got a bit more serious into this hobby. Well, that plus other factors which I won't exactly cover in this post (still not quite ready to talk about that). Regardless, things have been going decently well. I have a few frequent visitors who stick around in chat and talk to me. I'm not too fussed with whether I have a ton of people watching, as it's really a bad mental state to have.</p>
<p>I've been going through my Steam library one game at a time (well, kinda) to finish whatever I have. It's very rewarding, finally beating something and sharing that with others who enjoy your content. Hell, even if I didn't stream, it would be super nice to complete these games. That's the issue, though, is I rarely find time aside from streaming to even play games that have a campaign and finish them. Which, I mean, I do have the time, but it's the feeling of not having that and just not doing it.</p>
<p>I also have my own little Discord community that has a decent amount of people. We hang out occasionally in the voice chats, playing something like Guilty Gear, Melty Blood, Monster Hunter, etc. It's a great time as we joke around with each other.</p>
<h2> Programming</h2>
<p>So, if you recall, I work on <a href="https://github.com/lovebrew/lovepotion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">software known as LÖVE Potion</a>. If you don't, well, I don't blame you, since I haven't spoken much about it recently. I was talking with my friend piepie after I had been thinking about doing a whole new rewrite. I initially did a whole entire rewrite for version 2.0, but it was kind of bad in all honesty. I had the idea of common header files and splitting the source files up, but it was not great, especially for maintaining code down the line.</p>
<p>The new 3.0 rewrite fixes a lot of this by introducing templated classes for common data. Not every class gets this, but there are some core classes which required this. Some include the Source, Font, and Joystick objects (although some modules were also templated, such as Font and Image). There are also numerous quality of life fixes to the code's health, like using modern C++ types, like <code>std::span</code> and <code>std::unique_ptr</code>. These were mainly suggested by DeltaV, who noted a few ridiculous issues that were cropping up in the original 2.x codebase. This isn't all, though, as I've got support for Wii U coming (and it's working at the moment).</p>
<p>At the moment, I'm slowly working on implementing the graphics module. The 3DS can render textures and fonts right now, but I need to get that working on Switch. It's close, but there's a lot of functions left to implement, at least for Fonts. They are so obnoxiously complicated - not to say <em>overcomplicated</em>, just really annoying to implement. The Wii U version can only, at least graphically, clear the screen to your designated background color. However, all platforms can do a lot of the basic non-graphical functionalities. There is still no mouse module (obviously) and physics along with video aren't implemented. Physics has some warnings to fix, since it has some recursive call warnings I ran into and didn't know about until recently. Part of that is because the LÖVE codebase does not use  <code>this-&gt;</code> when handling class members, making it harder for me (or anyone) to really follow something like "is it the class member or parameter?".</p>
<h2> Writing</h2>
<p>Ah yeah, the novel I'm working on. The thing that I keep saying I'll work on and then I don't because I forget to. There really haven't been any updates regarding this, which sucks. Writing is a lot of fun since I get to unleash a ton of creativity onto some digital paper in Microsoft Word and just let it flow, see where it takes me. Every time I remind myself of this project, I sigh deeply and wish I had more motivation. I might just have been getting burnt out when writing too much as well, but either way, it's definitely something I truly want to keep working on. Maybe in 2023 I'll get motivation.</p>
<h2> Twitter</h2>
<p>My main Twitter account has been inactive for a <em>long</em> time. I don't really use it anymore, ever since I started streaming. I made a vtuber Twitter account, started following people, people followed me occassionally. All was good. Although it came to a point of two issues happening where I decided to stop using Twitter altogether.</p>
<p>Originally I thought nothing of the acquisition by Elon Musk, thinking it won't be that bad. I mean, I've obviously heard the stories™ of him buying stuff and then stuff going wrong. I merely didn't expect it to get as bad as it was, though. There's a lot that I could mention, but it's pretty obvious that if you tried looking up what's going wrong with Twitter currently and in the past month, it.. well, it's bad.</p>
<p>The other reasoning has to do with vtuber Twitter. I've mentioned this bit on my Mastodon account before and I'll say it again. I don't care if it's going to sound like a "hot take" either, because it's just unfortunately such a factual observation: there is so much negativity and drama going on it's not even funny. The amount of times that I've seen someone I follow <em>or</em> some random "Topics for you" pop up about vtubers where they do nothing but <em>complain</em> is absurd. Majority of the time they complain that their viewer counts are dropping, other times that their Twitter follower count is dipping. One person in particular started questioning themselves as to whether they were "good enough".</p>
<p>Now, to be fair, it's not just vtuber Twitter. There's probably a ton of accounts that do nothing but complain or be negative about stuff. However, I saw none of that on my original account. On top of that, sure I don't know what's going on in their lives that they might feel really down. Maybe they're depressed, maybe they're stressed from something, <em><em>I don't know</em></em>. What I <em>do</em> know is that online media like Twitter is not the place you should <em>really</em> be venting that kind of stuff, at the very least <em>often</em>. Repeatedly seeing this stuff even affected me and my streaming. I started to worry about viewer counts and how nobody followed me on Twitter and all. I escaped that mindset a few times, and I can keep doing it, but I would strongly prefer not needing to by separating myself from all of this.</p>
<p>I don't think I really need to mention the content that popped up where people were basically horny-posting pictures of their vtuber models. I'm not on vtuber Twitter - nor Twitter in general - to see that kind of content. Sure, sexual content sells and drives people to do stuff, but it's just sad to see if you have to pull that kind of stuff to gain an audience. I'm not sure if this or people constantly complaining is worse in terms of being an attention seeker, in all honestly. Regardless, if they want to  make that kind of content, by all means, do it, but I myself don't really approve of it.</p>
<p>I've moved over to Mastodon under a single account now. Programming updates for LÖVE Potion, streaming, personal stuff, etc are all posted on there.</p>
<h2> Conclusion</h2>
<p>That's about everything that's happened. Lots of good things this time around, less negative things. It's a step forward, but that's life sometimes. Not everything will always be a positive situation, but on the flip side, not everything can be negative. Hoping to do another update whenever and that it's something good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late-Night Turtle Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2023-08-15-late-night-tutel-time.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2023-08-15-late-night-tutel-time.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Late-Night Turtle Tuesday</source>
      <description>Late-Night Turtle Tuesday Time flies, eh? It&amp;apos;s been another eight months since I&amp;apos;ve posted anything, but here I am! Let&amp;apos;s start things off with the obvious: a fresh coat of paint. New Blog Theme One of the things I wanted to do recently was overhaul the blog design. The old one was good, don&amp;apos;t get me wrong, but realistically it had some issues. Mainly that GitHub Pages uses jekyll by default - which uses the ruby programming language. That itself isn&amp;apos;t bad, but installing ruby on Windows is like pulling teeth. I don&amp;apos;t know why it&amp;apos;s as hard as it was when I tried to do exactly that a couple of weeks ago. I debated on what static website generator to go with and decided to use vue-wordpress with this &amp;quot;hope&amp;quot; theme. It looks super slick. Took me a bit to set up almost everything I wanted to be as expected, but I got there at least.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Late-Night Turtle Tuesday</h1>
<p>Time flies, eh? It's been another eight months since I've posted anything, but here I am! Let's start things off with the obvious: a fresh coat of paint.</p>
<h2> New Blog Theme</h2>
<p>One of the things I wanted to do recently was overhaul the blog design. The old one was good, don't get me wrong, but realistically it had some issues. Mainly that GitHub Pages uses jekyll by default - which uses the ruby programming language. That itself isn't bad, but installing ruby on Windows is like pulling teeth. I don't know why it's as hard as it was when I tried to do exactly that a couple of weeks ago. I debated on what static website generator to go with and decided to use vue-wordpress with this "hope" theme. It looks super slick. Took me a bit to set up almost everything I wanted to be as expected, but I got there at least.</p>
<p>One thing you might want to check out is my VRChat Memories gallery. It <em>was</em> hidden away before, but I decided to make it more accessible now.</p>
<h2> Life</h2>
<p>This is probably the longer segment out of all the entire post. Lots happened. I recall blogging about how I lost my job back in late October, but the good news is that it only took two months to get a new one. I was extremely nervous, but confident going into the interviews for my current job and had made it to the code exam (dear <strong><em>god</em></strong> do I hate those)! This time around I prepared myself ahead of time as all I knew was I had to use C# and Selenium to create and run automation tests. I would be given a specific website and then I was on my own. I'm super glad that I passed that and became their top candidate because I am doing really well at my new company, compared to the prior one.</p>
<p>Furthermore, I got a new pet. Her name is Nala and she's a pit bull mix. I originally had a pet turtle for about a year, although if I'm being honest, it wasn't the right pet for me. My friend at the time had convinced me that getting the turtle would be good and low maintenance to a degree. However, after a while I had issues trying to take care of her because of some unknown reason. I mean, I did <em>try</em> to take care of the turtle, but she refused in a way. I wound up taking her back to PetSmart for adoption. Regardless, I adopted Nala from someone who listed her on the local animal shelter's website and she's been great. She is super sweet, loving and drives me crazy almost every day, but I love her and wouldn't trade her for the world.</p>
<p>Lastly, some news.. well everything here is news, but whatever. If you noticed, I at some point changed my blog title to my online alias (and the avatar too, but ¯\<em>(ツ)</em>/¯). Now, I've changed the blog name completely, sort of. Now assuming my parents never find my blog.. which they haven't yet (since I have spoken about the stuff that's happened between us on here): I'm trans. I originally figured this out about two years ago if memory serves. I spent a lot of time in VRChat - and I mean (<em>checks Steam</em>) 2,946 hours total in there. During that time I've only ever felt comfortable wearing female avatars. All the masculine ones just didn't even sit right with me. Mostly because their designs, but also because they didn't resonate well with how I felt. Over time, I wound up being mute around newer people depending on how I felt, (this was around 2020, a year after I started playing). People had mistaken me for a girl, which is understandable because I'm not speaking and also in a feminine avatar. After some time I came to my decision that I actually did enjoy people referring to me with she/her pronouns and it took a bit longer to settle into the idea of changing my name as well.</p>
<p>Initially I met some friends in a Vtuber's community (who are awesome people by the way) and they helped me ease into being more comfortable. After that, I changed my Twitch username to reflect my new name. I did tell some other friends online about all this, but that's not entirely important. At this point, only my one coworker knows, one cousin knows, my closest friends know, and my siblings and their spouses (and my sister-in-law's sister) know as well.</p>
<p>That all said, I have no idea if I'll ever tell my parents. My mother might be accepting, but my father - that's unlikely unless Hell froze over.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turtle Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2023-09-12-turtle-tuesday.html</link>
      <guid>https://TurtleP.github.io/posts/2023-09-12-turtle-tuesday.html</guid>
      <source url="https://TurtleP.github.io/rss.xml">Turtle Tuesday</source>
      <description>Turtle Tuesday LÖVE Potion 3.0 Pre-Release 5 It&amp;apos;s been some time since I last spoke about LÖVE Potion. If you&amp;apos;re unfamiliar with it, it&amp;apos;s a port and reimplementation of LÖVE2D for Nintendo consoles via homebrew. Currently the supported consoles include 3DS and Switch (and Wii U, t least on version 3.0). So today we&amp;apos;ll be talking about what&amp;apos;s new in the latest pre-release!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1> Turtle Tuesday</h1>
<h2> LÖVE Potion 3.0 Pre-Release 5</h2>
<p>It's been some time since I last spoke about LÖVE Potion. If you're unfamiliar with it, it's a port and reimplementation of <a href="https://love2d.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LÖVE2D</a> for Nintendo consoles via homebrew. Currently the supported consoles include 3DS and Switch (and Wii U, t least on version 3.0). So today we'll be talking about what's new in the latest pre-release!</p>
<h3> New 3DS Graphics Backend</h3>
<p>The main portion of the new pre-release has to do with the Nintendo 3DS version. Prior to this, it was using <a href="https://github.com/devkitpro/citro2d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">citro2d</a>. This is explicitly a 2D rendering library frontend of <a href="https://github.com/devkitpro/citro3d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">citro3d</a>.</p>
<p>Don't get me wrong, While citro2d has its purpose and is very useful, I had grown tired of its limitations for what I needed. I mean, sure, I had code from my friend piepie which helped with rendering n-gon polygons and other various shapes like arcs which utilized some magical math and triangle rendering with depth tricks. While this worked, it really annoyed me because it looked horrible inside the codebase. It was only as efficient as it could be, too. I also wanted it to be inline with the Switch and Wii U primitive rendering code.</p>
<p>I then proposed the idea to DeltaV about potentially swapping out citro2d for citro3d. After all, citro2d really just used citro3d in the grand scheme of things. If memory serves, the response was something like, "it shouldn't be too hard". That gave me the motivation to start making a test project in a stripped down environment. The good news is that everything just <em>worked</em>. The bad news.. I had some work on optimizing the rendering operations, but Delta helped me work that one out later on.</p>
<p>The new citro3d backend also let me refactor the Font class and now when users render text, can colorize their text as they could on normal LÖVE (and on Switch/Wii U).</p>
<h3> New LÖVE Objects</h3>
<p>Now with this new backend, I was able to safely add SpriteBatch objects and Meshes! Meshes are rather limited, though and I think the make them better I would definitely need to implement Buffers. So for now, I've released what I could do with the Mesh objects and will come back to them later when I've properly assessed how a Buffer is going to be dealt with.</p>
<p>SpriteBatches are super useful since you can pretty much draw any number of sprites with a specified texture at once. This is more optimal than doing several calls of <code>love.graphics.draw</code> for a given texture. I don't have the other numbers on me, but on hardware, I rendered the first <strong><em>90</em></strong> tiles of Super Mario Bros.'s 1-1 at 60fps. That doesn't sound like much, but for a Nintendo 3DS it is.</p>
<p>Likewise, Meshes allow users to create custom vertex buffers. You can set up the coordinates, texture uvs, and colors easily and draw them to the screen. They're mainly useful, I think, for 3D rendering but I could be wrong. I haven't used Meshes outside of the testing I did.</p>
<h2> Conclusion</h2>
<p>I'm stupidly proud of how far LÖVE Potion has come. I remember the early homebrew days where I used Ocarina of Time to launch what is now called "rednand" (redirected NAND). It used to be called "emunand" (emulated NAND) - which I think makes more sense, but that's not important. Then I found out that Videah was making LÖVE Potion and oh boy was I excited about that. I was always willing to test things for them and things rendering at like 15 FPS were quite exciting. Of course, at the time LÖVE Potion was written in C and didn't even follow what official LÖVE did (well, it did (mostly) but I mean code-wise to ensure compatability).</p>
<p>The next pre-release is likely going to add the physics module and compressed texture loading for Switch and Wii U. After that, the video module and then we'll be considered on-par with 2.x. Only thing after that is having people make games, find bugs, and fixing them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>